const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 32-year-old plumber developed pneumonia and was in the hospital for a week. The sputum was sent for culture and sensitivity. Laboratory reports showed Gram-positive cocci arranged in clusters. What is the causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 42-year-old woman was diagnosed with metastatic cervical cancer. Cervical cancers are mostly associated with human papillomavirus infections, which are now preventable with the help of vaccines. This vaccine is made up of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Live attenuated viruses","bool":false},{"option":"A mix of live and killed vaccines","bool":false},{"option":"Antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Killed viruses","bool":false},{"option":"Recombinant protein","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 45-year-old patient presented to the clinic with a postoperative surgical site infection after an emergency laparotomy. The sample was pus collected in a sterile syringe and sent to the laboratory for routine culture and sensitivity. Gram-stain revealed Gram-positive cocci in clusters with numerous pus cells. After 24 hours, beta-hemolytic colonies grew on the sheep blood agar plate, which was coagulase and catalase positive. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 15-year-old girl was brought to the emergency unit by her mother with complaints of sudden fever, headache, and stiff neck. Other symptoms were nausea, vomiting, increased sensitivity to light, and confusion. Cerebrospinal fluid was sent to the laboratory for routine culture and a detailed report. Microscopic examination showed diplococci organisms. Growth revealed grey colonies, which were catalase negative. Which of the following bacteria is most probably causing infection?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus viridians","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":true},{"option":"Enterococcus species","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Several vaccines are prepared using different bacterial components. Sometimes after vaccinating the population, vaccine-escape variants emerge. The most often component used in the development of bacterial vaccines is which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmid","bool":false},{"option":"Cell wall","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Cell membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Myc gene is implicated in which disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Neoplasia of fibroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Follicular lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Colon cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 32-year-old patient develops fever and myalgia. The physician orders a complete blood count (CBC). In case of a viral illness, the CBC will show an increase in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A young boy suffered from multiple infections. Family history was suggestive of antibody deficiency. His complete blood picture showed normal levels of T and B lymphocytes, however, serum immunoglobulin levels were markedly low. Which antibodies can activate the complement system?","answers":[{"option":"IgE and IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgA and IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgG and IgM","bool":true},{"option":"IgG and IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgD and IgA","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"25-year-old sexually active woman complaint of greenish-yellow vaginal discharge. Culture shows Gram-negative diplococci. What is the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which branch of forensics deals with performing autopsies and determining the cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Forensic serology","bool":false},{"option":"Forensic computer science","bool":false},{"option":"Forensic toxicology","bool":false},{"option":"Forensic pathology","bool":true},{"option":"Forensic sciences","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the main aim to perform an autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"To exclude poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"To exclude drug overdose","bool":false},{"option":"To look for any possible injuries","bool":false},{"option":"To identify the cause of death","bool":true},{"option":"To look for signs of life","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the demerit of arsenic as an ideal homicidal poison?","answers":[{"option":"It is rapid in action","bool":false},{"option":"It retards putrefaction","bool":true},{"option":"It has a characteristic taste","bool":false},{"option":"It is toxic in large doses","bool":false},{"option":"It is not easily avaliable","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"An ideal homicidal poison should not be which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Easily available","bool":false},{"option":"Should be palatable","bool":true},{"option":"Symptoms should resemble natural disease","bool":false},{"option":"Should be rapid in action","bool":false},{"option":"Tasteless and odorless","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Gastric lavage is contraindicated in which of the following poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"Dhatora","bool":false},{"option":"Corrosive","bool":true},{"option":"Snake","bool":false},{"option":"Organophosphorus","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"If water is used for gastric lavage, preferably it should be which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Luke warm","bool":false},{"option":"Saline","bool":false},{"option":"Sterilize","bool":false},{"option":"Cold","bool":false},{"option":"Warm","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"The antidotes which act by forming new less toxic compounds with poison are termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Chelating agents","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical antidotes","bool":true},{"option":"Universal antidotes","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological antidotes","bool":false},{"option":"Physical antidotes","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the treatment of choice for lead poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"Ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA)","bool":true},{"option":"Deferoxamine","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillamine","bool":false},{"option":"British Anti-Lewisite (BAL)","bool":false},{"option":"Activated charcoal","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the ideal position of patient while performing gastric lavage?","answers":[{"option":"Right lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Left lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Fowler's position","bool":false},{"option":"Supine","bool":false},{"option":"Prone","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What does the sympathetic stimulation of the iris cause?","answers":[{"option":"Viterous secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism (vision blurry or distorted)","bool":false},{"option":"Diplopia","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilation","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"In the division of the autonomic system, from where do parasympathetic fibers originate?","answers":[{"option":"The thoraco-lumbar spinal region","bool":false},{"option":"The cervico-lumbar region","bool":false},{"option":"The cranio-lumbar region","bool":false},{"option":"The cervico-thoracic region","bool":false},{"option":"The cranio-sacral regions","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect regarding pilocarpine?","answers":[{"option":"Increases body secretion","bool":false},{"option":"It is an alkaloid in nature","bool":false},{"option":"Duration of action is about 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"Acts on nicotonic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Drug of choice for emergency lowering intraocular pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which statement is not correct about bethanechol?","answers":[{"option":"Used for atony of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Structurally consists of carbamate and methylated choline","bool":false},{"option":"More specific for muscarinic receptors than nicotinic","bool":false},{"option":"Duration of action is about 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly degraded by acetylcholinesterase enzyme","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following does forensic medicine not deal with?","answers":[{"option":"Sexual assault","bool":false},{"option":"Abuse","bool":false},{"option":"Life and death","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanics","bool":true},{"option":"Medical malpractice","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 45-year-old female developed a fever with burning micturition. She was diagnosed with having urinary tract infection. The growth on the blood agar showed swarming organisms. Other chemical tests were performed. Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, oxidase-negative, non-lactose fermenting, H₂S-producing rod-shaped bacteria were isolated. Infection in the urinary tract may occur with indwelling catheters. Which organism is isolated in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Legionella","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":true},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 42-year-old patient was suspected of having tuberculosis. Microscopy showed acid-fast bacilli. What will be the medium of choice for the culture of these bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Eosin-methylene blue (EMB) agar","bool":false},{"option":"Blood agar","bool":false},{"option":"Löwenstein-Jensen agar","bool":true},{"option":"MacConkey agar","bool":false},{"option":"Chocolate agar","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following diseases is inherited in an X-linked recessive fashion?","answers":[{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Huntington disease","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Tumor-associated antigens are antigens present on the surface of the tumor cells. What is true for these antigens?","answers":[{"option":"Are always specific for specific tumors","bool":false},{"option":"Are immunologically undetectable","bool":false},{"option":"Only develop in tumors induced by viruses","bool":false},{"option":"Mimics antigens of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Can be recognized as non-self antigens","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) causes a reduction of T cell count to a level where the patient becomes severely deficient. HIV preferentially attacks which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Helper T cells","bool":true},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxic T cells","bool":false},{"option":"B cells","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"HLA-DR2 is a risk factor for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin-dependent (type I) diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A number of diseases are detected through antigen-antibody reactions. Which test utilizes this mechanism?","answers":[{"option":"Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)","bool":true},{"option":"Culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Genome sequencing","bool":false},{"option":"Probe analysis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A toxoid is an inactivated toxin that has lost its ability to cause disease but has retained its immunogenicity. The vaccines against which of these bacterial infections contains toxoid as an antigen?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diphtheria and tetanus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Regarding the oncogene of DNA tumor viruses, which of the following is most accurate?","answers":[{"option":"They interact with cellular proto-oncogenes and activates them","bool":false},{"option":"They encode cellular growth factors that activates S-phase DNA synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"They encode muscular growth factors that activates G-phase DNA synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"They encode protein kinase that phosphorylates p53 protein","bool":false},{"option":"They encode proteins that bind to the proteins coded by tumor suppressor genes","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"While reading the antimicrobial susceptibility results, the technologist noticed gaps in the growth of bacteria. Viruses that infect and kill the bacteria resemble the lunar lander and are composed of polyhedral heads, helical bodies, and legs that attach to the cell membrane so that they can transfer their genetic material. Bacteriophage belongs to which of the following classes of virus?","answers":[{"option":"Complex","bool":true},{"option":"Simple","bool":false},{"option":"Polyhedral","bool":false},{"option":"Spherical","bool":false},{"option":"Helical","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Tumor cells have several different mechanisms. These cells are mainly targeted by the T cells of the body. What is the function of the T cells?","answers":[{"option":"Phagocytose the cancer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Secrete lipid that stimulate growth and activation of both B and T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit the humoral immune response","bool":false},{"option":"Secrete perforins that create pores in the membrane of target cells","bool":true},{"option":"Activate humoral immunity against cancer cells","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 25-year-old woman has had several severe episodes of pneumonia in the past 5 months. She has not had frequent or unusual infections before the onset of this pneumonia. Which of the following is the most likely immunodeficiency that predisposes her to these infections?","answers":[{"option":"Mutation in the gene that encodes the C3a portion of the complement","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in B cells function","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation in one of the gene that encode the class Ⅰ MHC proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in cytotoxic T cells function","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced level of immunoglobulins","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 7-year-old boy presented in the outpatient department with complaints of malaise and lethargy for the last 10 days. He had become inattentive at school, anorexic, and lost 4 kg weight in the last 2 years. On examination, he was thin, anxious, and clinically anemic and also has moderate hepatosplenomegaly. The physician was suspecting a malignant etiology for all these complaints. Which cells are predominantly mediated in antitumor activity?","answers":[{"option":"CD 8 T lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"CD 4 T lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 3rd-year medical student attends a night-long educational retreat and develops a cough and fever. Several different attendees are sick with similar symptoms. Public health officials studying the outbreak suspect contaminated air-conditioning. What could be the cause?","answers":[{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 79-year-old man with end-stage Alzheimer's disease and dysphagia is taking multiple medications. Physical examination reveals xerostomia and a limited gag reflex. Which of the following routes of medication administration would provide the lowest serum drug concentrations?","answers":[{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous","bool":false},{"option":"Enteral","bool":true},{"option":"Intrathecal","bool":false},{"option":"Transdermal","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 28-year-old man with seborrheic dermatitis is prescribed a topical corticosteroid cream by his dermatologist in hopes of alleviating the chronic rash and erythema on the cheeks. Which of the following steps is most critical to achieving a therapeutic drug concentration in plasma?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Elimination","bool":false},{"option":"Absorption","bool":true},{"option":"Distribution","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosylation","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the advantage of a drug administered subcutaneously?","answers":[{"option":"Gives immediate drug action","bool":false},{"option":"Can be given when patient is in shock","bool":false},{"option":"Fast releasing drugs are given","bool":false},{"option":"For long duration of action","bool":true},{"option":"For short duration of action","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"What happens to a drug after the addition of glucuronic acid to it?","answers":[{"option":"Occurs at the same rate in adults and newborns","bool":false},{"option":"Involves cytochrome P450","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in its water solubility","bool":false},{"option":"Leads to inactivation of the drug","bool":true},{"option":"Its an example of phase I reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most important action of drug metabolism?","answers":[{"option":"To terminate drug action","bool":true},{"option":"Increase drug availability at receptor site","bool":false},{"option":"Increase binding of drug to plasma protein","bool":false},{"option":"Affect drugs bioavailability","bool":false},{"option":"Drug tolerance","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which organ is responsible for the majority of drug excretion?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 16-year-old girl suffering from seasonal rhinitis started therapy with loratadine, a drug that binds H1 histamine receptors. Which of the following terms best defines the intrinsic ability of a drug to bind to a receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Affinity","bool":true},{"option":"Efficacy","bool":false},{"option":"Potency","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor activation","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic activity","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Why is antagonism between adrenaline and histamine called physiological antagonism?","answers":[{"option":"Both affect many physiological processes","bool":false},{"option":"Both compete with same receptors","bool":false},{"option":"They have opposite physiological effects","bool":true},{"option":"Both are physiologically present in the body","bool":false},{"option":"They act on physiological receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which receptor type has 7 helical membrane spanning amino acid segments intracellular loops?","answers":[{"option":"Intrinsic ion channel containing receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine protein kinase receptor","bool":false},{"option":"G protein coupled receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Gene expression regulating receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Want receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"If a patient comes with a complain of nasal stuffiness, what would be the drug of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Pilocarpine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylepherine","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following features is not present in an ideal homicidal poison?","answers":[{"option":"Symptoms should resemble a natural disease","bool":false},{"option":"Should be palatable","bool":true},{"option":"Tasteless and odorless","bool":false},{"option":"Should be rapid in action","bool":false},{"option":"Easily available","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/foundation/2023","question":"Some viruses cause the downregulation of major histocompatibility complex (MHC) I complex to evade CD8 cells. Which of the following immune cells are involved in killing such cells with downregulated MHC I?","answers":[{"option":"T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Natural killer cells","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"B cells","bool":false}]}]
export default arr